冲啊，嫱嬉
Onward, Ohauncey!
向高塔顶端的房间冲啊
To the highest room of the tallest tower...
那儿我的公主正等待着 她英俊的查明王子来救她
...where my princess awaits rescue from her handsome Prince Oharming!
这比《情书》还难看 我讨厌晚餐剧场
This is worse than "Love Letters". I hate dinner theater!
我也是
Me, too.
就这里，嫱嬉
Whoa there, Ohauncey!
听！勇敢的查明王子来了
Hark! The brave Prince Oharming approacheth.
不要怕，美女 我会杀死那个怪物
Fear not, fair maiden. I shall slay the monster that guards you...
然后正当的坐上王位
...then take my place as rightful king.
她说什么？
What did she say?
是史莱克！
It's Shrek!
史莱克，耶！
Whoo, Shrek, yeah!
受死吧，恶心的怪物
Prepare, foul beast...
送你去一个你从没感受过的痛苦世界
...to enter into a world of pain with which you are not familiar!
祝你生日快乐 祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to thee Happy birthday to thee
你介意吗？
Do you mind?
你介意吗？无聊！
Do you mind? Boring!
受死吧，恶心的怪物
Prepare, foul beast...
总有一天你会后悔的
Someday you'll be sorry.
我们已经后悔了！
We already are!
妈咪
Mommy...
你是对的，我不能让这发生
You're right. I can't let this happen.
绝不
I can't!
我才是遥远国正当的国王
I am the rightful King of Far Far Away.
我向你保证，母亲…
And I promise you this, Mother...
我会恢复我王座的尊严
...I will restore dignity to my throne.
这一次
And this time,
没人能够阻止我
no one will stand in my way.
早上好
Good morning.
早晨的呼吸
Morning breath.
我知道，多美妙啊
I know. Isn't it wonderful?
早上好，早上好
Good morning, good morning
太阳照屁屁啦
The sun is shining through
早上好，你也早上好
Good morning, good morning To you
还有你！ 你！
And you! And you!
他们长得真快啊
They grow up so fast.
还不够快
Not fast enough.
你们将即位国王和王后
You'll be filling in for the King and Queen.
有几个场合需要你出席，殿下
Several functions require your attendance, sir.
太好了！我们开始吧
Great! Let's get started.
拜托，懒骨头 该行动了！
Oome on, lazybones. Time to get moving!
你真的需要一套睡衣裤
You need to get a pair ofjammies.
片名：《怪物史莱克3》
I got some sleep and I needed it
Not a lot, just a little bit
Someone's always trying to keep me from it
It's a crying shame
It's a royal pain in the neck
我封你为爵士
I knight thee.
如果你想继任国王 你就该表现的像个国王
If you're filling in for a king, you should look like one.
谁能进来帮史莱克弄一下造型？
Oan somebody come in and work on Shrek?
我看看我能怎么做
I will see what I can do.
耶，哇
Yeah, wow.
这真的有必要吗？
Is this really necessary?
当然有必要，菲奥娜
Quite necessary, Fiona.
- 我是史莱克，你个笨蛋 - 管他呢
- I'm Shrek, you twit. - Whatever.
好，这不是排练 我们来看看下面的骚动吧
This isn't a rehearsal, peoples. Let's see some hustle!
微笑，各位！微笑！
Smiles, everyone! Smiles!
我不知道我还能忍多久
I don't know how much longer I can keep this up.
对不起，但你能不能只是露齿一笑 再忍耐一下呢？
I'm sorry, but can you just try to grin and bear it?
等到爸爸好转就没事了
It's just until Dad gets better.
史莱克？
Shrek?
你看上去很英俊
You look handsome.
过来，你
Oome here, you.
我屁股痒的要命 穿了这猴子装我够不到
My butt is itching up a storm and I can't reach it in this monkey suit.
嘿，你！过来，你叫什么名字？
Hey, you! Oome here. What's your name?
费斗斯沃斯，殿下
Fiddlesworth, sir.
好极了
Perfect.
女士们先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
有请菲奥娜公主和史莱克殿下
...Princess Fiona and Sir Shrek!
啊！就是那里
Ahh! You've got it.
再左边一点
A little to the left.
就是那里，很好
That's it! That's good.
哦，耶，挠，就是那个
Oh, yeah! Scratch that thing! You're on it.
史莱克！
Shrek!
我的眼睛！
My eye!
你在干吗？
What are you doing?
菲奥娜！
Fiona!
- 你还好吗？ - 嗯，我很好
- Are you okay? - Yeah. I'm fine.
哦，虾，我的最爱
Shrimp! My favorite!
- 我受够了，我们走！ - 冷静
- That's it! We're leaving! - Oalm down.
冷静？你认为我们是在跟谁开玩笑？ 我是个怪物
Oalm down? Who do you think we're kidding? I am an ogre.
我不适合做这个，菲奥娜 永远都不适合
I'm not cut out for this, Fiona, and I never will be.
我认为会好的
I think that went well.
驴子！
Donkey!
别这样，史莱克！
Oome on, Shrek!
有些人就是不识相
Some people just don't understand boundaries.
想想，再过几天我们就能回家去了
Just think. A couple more days and we'll be back home...
回到我们那点缀着菌菇 充满着虫子的小木屋了
...in our vermin-filled shack strewn with fungus...
充满着泥土的气息和懒散
...and filled with the stench of mud and neglect.
你让我好像回到了那里
You had me at "vermin-filled".
也许地上还有一串小脚印
And, um... maybe even the pitter-patter of little feet on the floor.
对，沼泽里的老鼠开始产卵
That's right, the swamp rats will be spawning.
不
Uh, no.
我想到的是比沼泽鼠更大一点的
What I'm thinking of is a little bigger than a swamp rat.
驴子？
Donkey?
不，史莱克，假设，理论上的…
No, Shrek. What if, theoretically...
是小怪物的小脚印？
...they were little ogre feet?
亲爱的，我们要理智对待这个事情
Honey, let's be rational about this.
你最近看到过婴儿吗？
Have you seen a baby lately?
他们只会吃然后拉，还有哭
They just eat and poop, and they cry...
当他们拉的时候哭 哭的时候拉
...then they cry when they poop and poop when they cry.
现在，想像一下怪物婴儿
Now, imagine an ogre baby.
他们哭的更厉害，拉的也更厉害
They extra-cry and they extra-poop.
史莱克，你从没想过拥有一个家庭吗？
Shrek, don't you ever think about having a family?
现在，你就是我的家庭
Right now, you're my family.
那么急干吗，有人要死了吗
Somebody better be dying.
我快要死了
I'm dying.
哈罗德？
Harold?
不要忘了付钱给园丁，莉莉安
Don't forget to pay the gardener, Lillian.
当然，亲爱的
Of course, darling.
菲奥娜
Fiona.
在，爸爸？
Yes, Daddy?
我知道我过去错怪了你很多
I know I made many mistakes with you.
没事的
It's okay.
但你对史莱克的爱…
But your love for Shrek has...
教会了我很多
...taught me much.
我亲爱的孩子…
My dear boy...
我很自豪称你为我的儿子
...I am proud to call you my son.
我也很自豪称你为我的青蛙…
And I'm proud to call you my frog...
…国王岳父
...King dad-in-law.
现在有件事要处理
Now there is a matter of business to attend to.
青蛙国王…死了
The Frog King... is dead.
戴好你的帽子，傻瓜
Put your hat back on, fool.
史莱克…
Shrek...
请来这边
...please come hither.
是的，爸爸？
Yeah, Dad?
王国需要一位新的国王
This kingdom needs a new king.
你和菲奥娜将即位王座
You and Fiona are next in line for the throne.
即位？你看，爸爸 这就是为什么人民爱戴你的原因
Next in line. You see, Dad, that's why people love you.
即使临终之时，你还在开玩笑
Even on your deathbed, you're still making jokes.
得了吧，爸爸，怪物做国王？
Oome on, Dad. An ogre as king?
这不是个好主意
That's not such a good idea.
必须有另外的人来继任，任何人！
There must be somebody else. Anybody!
除了你，只有一个继承人
Aside from you, there is only one remaining heir.
真的？是谁？爸爸
Really? Who is he, Dad?
他叫…
His name is...
叫…
...is...
他叫什么？
What's his name?
叫…
...is...
爸爸！
Daddy!
他叫亚瑟
His name is Arthur.
亚瑟？
Arthur?
我知道你会…处理好这件事的
I know you'll do...
...what's right.
哈罗德？
Harold?
爸爸？爸爸！
Dad? Dad!
爸爸？
Dad?
脱帽，朋友
Do your thing, man.
When you were young and your heart
Was an open book
You used to say live and let live
You know you did, you know you did You know you did
But if this ever changing world In which we live in
Makes you give in and cry
Say live and let die
Live and let die
Hey, lady You, lady
Cursing at your life
You're a discontented mother
And a regimented wife
王子想在这儿喝酒该怎么做呢？
What does a prince have to do to get a drink here?
啊，梅波
Ah, Mabel!
为什么他们叫你丑陋的继姐 我一直不明白
Why they call you an ugly stepsister, I'll never know.
多丽丝呢？今晚休息？
Where's Doris? Taking the night off?
这里不欢迎她，你也一样
She's not welcome here, and neither are you.
你想要干吗，查明？
What do you want, Oharming?
没什么，想找个机会赎罪
Not much. Just a chance at redemption.
一杯鸡尾酒
And a Fuzzy Navel.
给在场所有我的朋友们一杯鸡尾酒
And Fuzzy Navels for all my friends!
我们不是你的朋友
We're not your friends.
你不属于这里
You don't belong here.
你说得对，但我意思是 有谁属于这里呢？
You're absolutely right, but, I mean, do any of us?
在他脸上做个记号
Do a number on his face.
等等，等等 我们其实都一样
Wait, wait, wait! We are more alike than you think.
丑巫婆！七个小矮人救了白雪公主 然后发生了什么？
Wicked Witch! The Seven Dwarfs saved Snow White, and what happened?
这和你有什么关系？
Oh, what's it to you?
他们给了你最不公平的待遇
They left you the unfairest of them all.
现在你在这里 靠台球来换取你的下一顿饭
Now here you are, hustling pool to get your next meal.
那感觉怎样？
How does that feel?
很不公平
Pretty unfair.
还有你！
And you!
你的明星木偶放弃了表演 去寻找他的父亲
Your star puppet abandons the show to go and find his father.
我讨厌那个小木头玩偶
I hate that little wooden puppet.
还有你铁钩
And Hook.
还需要我说吗？
Need I say more?
- 你，弗朗皮克斯金 - 是兰佩尔斯汀斯金
- And you, Frumpypigskin! - Rumpelstiltskin.
他们保证你的长子又在哪里呢？
Where's that firstborn you were promised?
梅波，记住你是怎么不能把你的肥脚丫…
Mabel. Remember how you couldn't get your little fat foot...
穿进那个小的水晶鞋的吗？
...into that tiny glass slipper?
灰姑娘此刻正在遥远国…
Oinderella is in Far Far Away right now...
正吃着糖果 和那些和你作对的人快乐着呢
...eating bonbons, cavorting with every last fairy tale creature...
...that has ever done you wrong!
从前，一些人把我们称为失败者
Once upon a time, someone decided that we were the losers.
但每个故事都有两面
But there are two sides to every story...
我们的那一面还没有讲给人听
...and our side has not been told!
所以谁要加入我？谁想要翻身一次？
So who will join me? Who wants to come out on top for once?
谁想要…
Who wants their...
从此以后一直幸福？
..."happily ever after"?
这边，绅士们
This way, gents.
人在江湖，身不由己啊
It's out of my hands, senorita. The winds of fate have blown on my destiny.
但我永远不会忘记你 你是我一生的爱
But I will never forget you. You are the love of my life.
你也是
As are you.
还有你
And, uh, you.
我不认识你，但我也愿意
I don't know you, but I'd like to.
我要走了
I got to go!
我也不想离开你们
I don't wanna leave you either.
但你知道史莱克是怎样的 这兄弟没有我就不行
But you know how Shrek is. The dude's lost without me.
不要担心，我会每天给你快递香吻的
But don't worry. I'll send you airmail kisses every day!
要坚强，孩子们
Be strong, babies.
椰子，花生，听妈妈的话
Ooco, Peanut, listen to your mama.
香蕉，不要再在你妹妹头上烤蜜饯了哦
Bananas, no roasting marshmallows on your sister's head.
那才是我的乖孩子
That's my special boy!
都过来，给你们老爸一个大大的拥抱
Oome here, all of you! Give your daddy a big hug!
史莱克？
Shrek?
也许你该留下继任国王
Maybe you should just stay and be King.
得了吧，我怎么可能来管理国家
Oome on. There's no way I could run a kingdom.
你的堂弟亚瑟才是个完美的选择
That's why your cousin Arthur is a perfect choice.
不是的，你知道…
It's not that. You see...
如果他给我麻烦 我可以说服他给他讲道理
And if he gives me trouble, I always have persuasion and reason.
这法宝是说服力，这法宝是讲道理
Here's persuasion... and here's reason.
菲奥娜…
Fiona...
很快就只有你和我…
...soon it's just going to be you, me...
还有我们的沼泽
...and our swamp.
不只是你和我
It's not going to be just you and me.
上船啦！
All aboard!
会的，我保证
It will be. I promise.
我爱你
I love you.
[我们爱你，爸爸]
太美了
That's lovely.
再见，孩子们！
Bye-bye, babies!
史莱克！
Shrek!
- 等等 - 什么？
- Wait! - What is it?
我…
I'm... I'm...
我也爱你，亲爱的！
I love you, too, honey!
不！我说，我…
No! I said I'm...
你什么？
You're what?
我说我怀孕了！
I said I'm pregnant!
那是什么？
What was that?
你要做父亲了！
You're going to be a father!
太好了！
That's great!
真的？我很高兴你这么想
Really? I'm glad you think so!
我爱你！
I love you!
Yeah!
我也爱你！
Me, too! You!
我要做叔叔了！ 我要做叔叔了！
I'm going to be an uncle! I'm going to be an uncle!
你，我的朋友，将成为皇室…
And you, my friend, are royally...
家
Home.
史莱克！
Shrek!
菲奥娜！
Fiona!
菲奥娜？
Fiona?
哦，不
Oh, no.
我一直说，能吃下去就别吐出来
Better out than in, I always say.
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
没事的，会没事的
It's okay. It's gonna be all right.
住手，嘿，等等！
Stop! Hey, wait!
驴子！驴子！
Donkey. Donkey!
醒醒！
Wake up!
爸爸！
Dada!
史莱克？你好吧？
Shrek! Are you okay?
我不敢相信我要做父亲了 这怎么发生的？
I can't believe I'm going to be a father. How did this happen?
请允许我解释，当一个男人 对一个女人有感觉时…
Allow me to explain. When a man has feelings for a woman...
一股强大的冲动占据着他
...a powerful urge sweeps over him.
我知道这是怎么发生的
I know how it happened.
我只是不敢相信
I just can't believe it.
这是怎么发生的？
How does it happen?
And the cat's in the cradle and the silver spoon
Little Boy Blue and the Man in the Moon
When you coming home, son? I don't know when
But we'll get together then, Dad.
驴子！你能不能只唱…
Donkey! Oan you just cut to the part
让我感觉舒服的部分？
where you're supposed to make me feel better?
你知道我很爱菲奥娜，对吧，老大？
You know I love Fiona, boss. Right?
我要说的是你，我还有我堂弟的船…
What I am talking about is you, me, my cousin's boat...
再来一壶冰酒，加上两个礼拜的钓鱼
...an ice cold pitcher of mojitos and two weeks of nothing but fishing.
不要听他的！
Don't listen to him!
有孩子不会毁掉你的生活
Having a baby isn't going to ruin your life.
我担心的不是毁掉我的生活 而是孩子的生活
It's not my life I'm worried about ruining, it's the kid's.
你听到过别人说“像怪物一样美”…
When have you ever heard the phrase "as sweet as an ogre"...
或是”像怪物一样有教养“
...or "as nurturing as an ogre"...
或是”你会喜欢我爸爸的 他是个真正的怪物“这样的话吗？
...or "You'll love my dad. He's a real ogre."
好，我懂了
Okay. I get it.
虽然这不会那么容易 但你有我们的帮助
It's not going to be easy. But you got us to help you.
那倒是
That's true.
命中注定的
I'm doomed.
你会好的
You'll be fine.
你完了
You're finished.
哦，完…成了你的旅程
Uh, with yourjourney.
”沃…册特…斯里？“ 听上去很新奇！
"Wor-ces-ters-shiree"? Now that sounds fancy!
是沃塞斯特雷
It's Worcestershire.
和那个沙司牌子一样？
Like the sauce?
好香！
It's spicy!
他们肯定在期待我们
They must be expecting us.
这个沃什么的到底是个什么地方？
What in the shista-shire kind of place is this?
我的胃好疼还有我的手掌在出汗 一定是个中学
Well, my stomach aches and my palms just got sweaty. Must be a high school.
中学？
High school?
好了吗？开始
Ready? Okay!
“你想到达艺术的顶端吗?”
Wherefore art thou headed, to the top?
“是啊，我们能，我们能！ 有什么能阻止你呢？”
Yeah, we think so, we think so! And dost thou thinkest thine can be stopped?
“不，没有，没有”
Nay, we thinkst not, we thinkst not!
好，佩西，脱缰一样冲吧
All right, Mr. Percival, ease up on the reins.
伙计，别烧了我的乳香和没药
For lo, bro, don't burn all my frankincense and myrrh.
那平底鞋和混乱场面让我感到恶心
I'm feeling nauseous from memories of wedgies and swirlies!
你不穿内裤哪来的平底鞋呢？
How did you receive wedgies when you are clearly not the wearer of underpants?
有些事是不言而喻的
Let's just say some things are better left unsaid.
所以我要说“我宁愿得黑死病 也不愿和你出去约会”
So I was all like, "I'd rather get the black plague than go out with you."
- 哦，绝对的 - 你说什么
- Oh, totally. - Pardon me.
- 绝对恶心 - 是啊
- Totally ew-eth. - Yeah, totally.
我刚把我的角色等级升到了+3超能力
I just altered my character level to +3 superb-ability.
嗨，我们在找一个叫…
Hi. We're looking for someone named...
谁弄了+9的傀儡符咒 又召唤了怪物和四足怪？
Who rolled a +9 dork spell and summoned the beast and his quadruped?
我知道你们很忙没时间 但你们能告诉我哪里能找到亚瑟吗？
I know you're busy not fitting in, but can you tell me where I can find Arthur?
他在那里
He's over there.
没有比胜利更美味的了
There is no sweeter taste on thy tongue than victory!
强壮，英俊，长着一张领导者的脸
Strong, handsome, face of a leader.
亚瑟长得不就像一位国王吗？
Does Arthur look like a king or what?
不好意思
Sorry.
你刚才说你在找亚瑟？
Did you say you were looking for Arthur?
显而易见的
That information is on a need-to-know basis.
这是顶级机密！
It's top secret!
先生们，我们走 去洗澡！
Now, gentlemen, let's away. To the showers!
你好，陛下
Greetings, Your Majesty.
今天是你的幸运日
This is your lucky day.
你是什么东西？
What are you supposed to be?
某种变异的巨大妖精还是什么？
Some kind of giant mutant leprechaun or something?
变异？你真搞笑
Giant mutant... You made a funny.
放我下来，怪物！
Unhand me, monster!
不要动，亚瑟
Stop squirming, Arthur.
我不是亚瑟
I'm not Arthur.
我是兰斯洛特
I am Lancelot.
那边的那个傻瓜才是亚瑟
That dork over there is Arthur.
这…真的是…很尴尬
This is, like, totally embarrassing...
但蒂凡尼对你很有兴趣
...but Tiffany thinkest thou vex her so soothly.
她想你会不会愿意邀请她去“回归舞会”
She thought perchance thou would ask her to the Homecoming Dance.
什么？
Excuse me?
这样的，她对大学男生 还有神话怪物很感兴趣
Like, whatever. She's into college guys and mythical creatures.
哦，亚瑟…
Oh, Arthur...
出来，出来，不管你在哪里
...come out, come out, wherever you are!
你们最好走远点，混蛋！
You better run, you little punk no-goodniks!
贫嘴驴短内裤的日子结束了
The days of Donkey Dumpy Drawers are over!
等等
Hold it.
我们是来参加吉祥物比赛的
We're here for the mascot contest.
我们也是来参加吉祥物比赛的
We're here for the mascot contest, too.
这是服装吗？
This is a costume?
我弄了整整一晚上呢
Worked on it all night long.
看上去象真的一样
Looks pretty real to me.
如果他是真的，我能这样做吗？
If he were real, could I do this?
或是这样？
Or this?
如果是真的，早就疼得要命了
If it were real, that would have been agonizingly painful.
- 看好这个！ - 够了，孩子们
- Now watch this! - That's quite enough, boys.
谢谢普林波顿教授和他的“只要说不”演讲
Thank you to Professor Primbottom and his lecture...
...on "just say nay".
现在不再唆，让我们热烈…
And now, without further ado, let's give a warm Worcestershire hoozah...
欢迎吉祥物大赛的冠军…
...to the winner of our mascot contest, the...
怪物？
...ogre?
对，我是新的吉祥物
That's right. I'm the new mascot.
我们还是热烈的为那些…
So let's really try and beat the other guys at...
不知道在干吗的人鼓掌吧！
...whatever it is they're doing!
这太不正统了
This is all a bit unorthodox...
哪里我能找到亚瑟・潘德拉根？
Where can I find Arthur Pendragon?
嘿，等等…
Hey, wait...
经典
Olassic.
你该为自己感到羞愧！
You should be ashamed of yourself!
不是我干的，是他们干的
I didn't do it. They did.
请不要吃掉我
Please don't eat me.
吃掉他！吃掉他！吃掉他！
Eat him! Eat him! Eat him!
我不是来吃他的！
I'm not here to eat him!
你该打包整理你的行李了
Time to pack up your toothbrush and jammies.
你将是遥远国新的国王
You're the new King of Far Far Away.
什么？
What?
亚蒂王？ 他更像是笨蛋村的村长！
Artie a king? More like the Mayor of Loserville!
Burn.
这是真的吗？
Is this for real?
当然，清理好你的衣柜，孩子 你的王国等着你管理
Absolutely. Olean out your locker, kid. You have a kingdom to run.
等等…我真的是唯一的继承人？
So, wait... l'm really the only heir?
唯一的一个
The one and only.
等我一下
Give me a second.
我的人民…
My good people...
这是非常好的一课
...there's a lesson here for all of us.
下一次你们准备把一个小孩的头 泡在尿壶里的时候，请停下想想
Next time you're about to dunk a kid's head in a chamber pot, stop and think,
“嘿，也许这个家伙也是有感情的”
"Hey, maybe this guy has feelings.
“也许我该放他一马”
Maybe I should cut him some slack.
“也许因为…也许…”
'Oause maybe... just maybe...
“这家伙会成为，有可能，成为国王？”
...this guy's gonna turn out to be, I don't know, a king?
也许他颁布的第一个皇家法令就是 放逐那些曾经戏弄过他的人
Maybe his first royal decree will be to banish everyone who ever picked on him."
我在看着你，骑马队！
I'm looking at you, jousting team!
还有奎因？哦，奎因
And Guin? Oh, Guin.
我一直爱着你
I've always loved you.
好朋友们，我很伤心，但…
Good friends, it breaks my heart, but...
你们继续享受在这牢狱里的日子吧 而我将去统治一个自由的世界
...enjoy your stay here in prison while I rule the free world!
好了，我们不要搞的太过了
Okay, let's not overdo it.
我将建立我的城市，摇滚的人民
I'm building my city, people... on rock 'n' roll!
你做得太过了
You just overdid it.
看看你啊！
Look at you!
你看上去真可爱
You look darling.
太尊贵了，看她
Just precious. Look at her.
从你怀孕后有什么特别渴望的吗？
Any cravings since you got pregnant?
没，一点也没
No. Not at all.
你们闻到火腿的味道了吗？
Do you smell ham?
现在是礼物时间！
It's present time!
菲奥娜，请先打开我的礼物 前面的那个
Fiona, please open mine first. It's the one in front.
“恭喜你要有调皮鬼了” 哦，调皮鬼！
"Oongratulations on your new mess mak..." Oh, mess maker!
“希望这对你有用，爱你的，灰姑娘”
"Hopefully this helps. Love, Oinderella."
- 看看那个！ - 那是什么？
- Look at that! - What is it?
用来打扫大便的
It's for the poopies.
等等…婴儿的大便？
Wait... babies poop?
每个人都大便的，睡美人
Everyone poops, Beauty.
菲奥娜！
Fiona!
我们也都准备了一个小礼物
We all chipped in for a little present, too.
哒…哒！
Ta-da!
你知道孩子会喜欢的 因为我也喜欢！
You know the baby will love it, because I do!
伙计们，你们真是太好了，谢谢
Guys, that's so sweet. Thank you.
这是谁给的？
Who's this one from?
我给你最大的礼物 因为爱你也最深
I got you the biggest one, because I love you most.
“我也想有个，爱你的，白雪公主”
"Have one on me. Love, Snow White."
这是什么？
What is it?
专职婴儿保姆
He's a live-in babysitter.
宝宝在哪里？
Where's the baby?
你太好了，白雪公主 但我不能收下
You're too kind, Snow, but I can't accept this.
没什么的，我家里还有6个呢
It's nothing. I have six more at home.
- 他能做什么？ - 打扫
- What does he do? - Oleaning.
- 喂饭 - 打嗝
- Feeding. - Burping.
那我和史莱克该干吗？
So, what are Shrek and I supposed to do?
享受你们的婚姻
Work on your marriage.
谢谢，莴苣姑娘 那是什么意思？
Thanks, Rapunzel. What's that supposed to mean?
得了，菲奥娜 你知道怎么回事
Oome on now, Fiona. You know what happens.
你一直很劳累
You're tired all the time.
失去了真正的自己
You start letting yourself go.
妊娠纹
Stretch marks.
再也没有浪漫生活
Say goodbye to romance.
不好意思，但你们中有几个有孩子呢？
I'm sorry, but how many of you have kids?
她说的对
She's right!
孩子只会加深史莱克和菲奥娜之间的爱
A baby will only strengthen the love Shrek and Fiona have.
当你告诉史莱克时，他是什么反应？
How did Shrek react when you told him?
当他第一次知道时，他说…
When he first found out, Shrek said...
冲啊，我的新朋友们！ 为了我们永远的幸福生活！
Onward, my new friends! To our happily ever afters!
现在，投弹！
Now... bombs away!
好，好，好，如果这不是皮特・潘
Well, well, well. If it isn't Peter Pan.
- 他不叫皮特 - 闭嘴，温迪
- His name's not Peter. - Shut it, Wendy.
掠夺够了！向城堡冲啊！
Enough pillaging! To the castle!
你们快走！照顾好孩子！
You go! Take care of the baby!
大家冷静！我们要死了！
Everybody stay calm! We're going to die!
大家快进去！快！
Everyone in! Now!
快，撞开！
Oome on! Put some back into it!
我们没时间了，快走！
We don't have time. Now go!
快点，女士们！
Quickly, ladies!
我们尽量拖延住他们！
We'll hold them off as long as we can!
史莱克和菲奥娜在哪里？
Where are Shrek and Fiona?
从没听说过这名字
The name doesn't ring a bell.
没听过
No bell.
我建议你们这群蠢蛋…
I suggest you freaks cooperate...
好好的跟遥远国的新国王合作！
...with the new King of Far Far Away!
你唯一可以成为的是傻瓜国的国王！
The only thing you're ever gonna be king of is King of the Stupids!
- 铁钩！ - 在！
- Hook! - Right!
来吧，你这小饼干
Avast, ye cookie.
说话呀
Start talking.
- 金吉！ - 爸爸！
- Gingy! - Papa!
大家坐下！
Settle down now.
坐上漂亮船去买棒棒糖
On the good ship Lollipop
去糖果店的旅程真是太美好了
It's a sweet trip to the candy shop
你！
You!
你不会说谎的
You can't lie.
告诉我，木偶…史莱克在哪里？
So tell me, puppet... where is Shrek?
那…我不知道他不在哪里
Well... I don't know where he's not.
你不知道史莱克在哪里？
You don't know where Shrek is?
不能不正确的假定…
It wouldn't be inaccurate to assume...
我不能确切的不说出 或部分不几乎是不正确
...that I couldn't exactly not say that is or isn't almost partially incorrect.
那你肯定是知道他在哪里！
So you do know where he is!
恰恰相反，我可能或多或少
On the contrary, I'm possibly more or less
不确定的不完全否定这个意思
not definitely rejecting the idea
that in no way, with any amount of uncertainty...
住嘴！
Stop it!
我不知道他不应该在哪里
...I do not know where he shouldn't be.
如果确实那不是他不在的地方
If that indeed wasn't where he isn't.
即使他不是不在我所知道的他在的地方 这意味着……
Even if he wasn't not where I knew he was, it could mean...
坐上漂亮的船去买棒棒糖
On the good ship Lollipop
够了！史莱克出去要把下一任的国王带回来
Enough! Shrek went off to bring back the next heir!
他要带回下一任的国王？
He's bringing back the next heir?
不！
No!
铁钩！去除掉这个新“国王”
Hook! Get rid of this new "King".
但把史莱克带来给我
But bring Shrek to me.
我给他准备了特别的主意
I have something special in mind for him.
他绝不会被你的诡计陷害的
He'll never fall for your tricks!
哦，孩子
Oh, boy.
我真不敢相信，我，一个国王？
I can't believe it. Me, a king?
我知道我出身皇室，但…
I knew I came from royalty, but...
我原以为大家都忘记了我
...I figured everyone forgot about me.
哦，不，实际上是国王亲自点名要你继任的
Oh, no. In fact the King asked for you personally.
真的？哇
Really? Wow.
但我知道这不是玩游戏
But I know it's not all fun and games.
事实上这确实是玩游戏
It really is all fun and games, actually.
当然，你要册封一些新英雄 启航一两艘舰船
Sure, you have to knight a few heroes, launch a ship or two.
顺便说一下，你务必确保 能用瓶子击中轮船
By the way, make sure you hit the boat just right with the bottle.
任何傻瓜都能用一个瓶子击中一艘轮船
Any idiot can hit a boat with a bottle.
我听说这其实要比看上去来的困难
Well, I've heard it's harder than it looks.
这真是太棒了
This is going to be huge.
聚会，公主，城堡，公主
Parties, princesses, castles. Princesses.
你会生活的很奢侈
You'll be living in the lap of luxury.
最好的厨师会等候你的命令
The finest chefs will wait for your order.
幸运的是，你还会有皇家食物品尝师
And fortunately, you'll have the royal food tasters.
他们是做什么的？
What do they do?
在国王吃东西前先品尝 确保食物没有被放毒
Taste the food before the King eats, to make sure it's not poisoned.
- 放毒？ - 或者太咸了
- Poisoned? - Or too salty.
不要担心，你的侍卫会保护你的安全
Don't worry. Your bodyguards will keep you safe.
他们愿意随时随地的牺牲自己…
All of them willing at a moment's notice
为了保护你的生命
to lay down their lives out of devotion to you.
真的？
Really?
整个国家都指望着你的智慧和指引
The whole kingdom will look to you for wisdom and guidance.
确保他们不会死于饥饿
Make sure they don't die of famine!
- 或是瘟疫 - 瘟疫太糟了
- Or plague. - Plague is bad.
咳嗽，呻吟，化脓溃疡
The coughing, the groaning, the festering sores.
化脓溃疡！ 你真是个有趣的可爱小猫
Festering sores! You are one funny kitty cat.
我刚才说什么了？
What did I say?
我们不想让亚蒂有错误的想法
We don't want Artie getting the wrong idea.
亚蒂？
Artie?
够郁闷的！
There goes my hip!
亚蒂！你在干吗？
Artie! What are you doing?
你看我在干吗？！
What does it look like?!
这真的不是你该做的
This really isn't up to you.
我对于当国王一无所知
I don't know anything about being king!
你会慢慢学会的！
You'll learn on the job!
不好意思，但我准备回去
Sorry, but I'm going back.
回去哪里？去当一个失败者？
Back to what? Being a loser?
看看你做的好事！
Now look what you did!
看看我做的好事？ 是谁在掌舵啊，大幅？
Look what I did? Who's holding the wheel, chief?
史莱克！
Shrek!
上岸！
Land ho!
真是丢脸
How humiliating.
哦，做得好，殿下
Oh, nice going, Your Highness.
现在成了“殿下”？ 刚才谁在叫“失败者”？
Now it's "Your Highness"? What happened to "loser"?
如果你认为这就能使你离开 那是不可能的
If you think this is getting you out of anything, it isn't.
我们无论如何会回到遥远国
We're heading back to Far Far Away one way or another...
而你将会成为父亲！
...and you're going to be a father!
什么？
What?
你刚才说“父亲”
You just said "father".
国王！你将会成为国王！
King! You're going to be king!
“你会成为国王”是啊，对的
"You're going to be king!" Yeah, right.
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
远远…的离开你
Far Far Away... from you!
回来，年轻人！
Get back here, young man!
老大？我认为他不回来了
Boss? I don't think he's coming back.
也许这是对的 他真的不是当国王的料
Maybe it's for the best. He's not exactly king material.
那你计划什么时候告诉他 你才应该当国王？
When did you plan to tell him you were supposed to be king?
得了，我为什么要那么做？
Oome on. Why would I do that?
而且，他做国王比我强十倍
Besides, he'll be ten times better at it than me.
如果你想要他跟你走 你需要改变你的战略
Then change your tactics if you want to get anywhere with him.
你说得对，驴子
You're right, Donkey.
这个怎样？
What about this?
- 史莱克！ - 得了，只是个玩笑
- Shrek! - Oome on. It's just a joke.
算是吧…
Still...
听着，亚蒂
Listen, Artie.
如果你觉得这整件事情很糟糕 我理解你，兄弟
If you think this whole mad scene ain't dope, I feel you, dude.
我不想难为你，让你心烦意乱
I'm not trying to get up in your grill or raise your roof.
但我想要说的是，你…
But what I am screamin' is, yo...
想想这整个事情，孩子！
...check out this kazing thazing, bazaby!
如果这不合理，或是我所说的…
If it doesn't groove, or what I'm saying
不够真诚，你可以直接说 “哦，不，你别”
ain't straight trippin', say, "Oh, no, you didn't!
“你快让我疯了”
You're getting on my last nerve."
那么我会知道这是… 知道这是不值得的
And then I'll know it's... I'll know it's wack!
救命啊！
Help!
我被一个怪物绑架了 他想跟我拉关系
I've been kidnapped by a monster who's trying to relate to me!
- 亚蒂，等等 - 快点！救命！有人吗？
- Artie, wait. - Oome on! Help! Hello?
大家好，宇宙的孩子们
Greetings, cosmic children of the universe.
欢迎来到我的宁静之处
Welcome to my serenity circle.
请不要带坏的电颤琴到康复小屋里来
Please leave any bad vibes outside the healing vortex.
现在准备好…
Now prepare to...
我就知道我该拿保修单的！
I knew I should have got that warranty!
梅林先生？
Mr. Merlin?
你认识这个人？
You know this guy?
是啊，他没神经失常前 是学校里的魔法老师
Yeah. He was the school magic teacher, until he had his nervous breakdown.
专业点讲，我只是3等疲劳
Technically, I was merely a victim of a level 3 fatigue.
在我的理疗师
At the request of my therapist,
和学校方面要求下 我退休来享受宁静世界
and the school authorities, I retired to the tranquility of nature
为了发现我神圣的目标
to discover my divine purpose.
谁有兴趣来点小吃或是饮料吗？
Oan I interest anyone in a snack or beverage?
哦，不了
Uh, no.
你确定不想尝尝我的烤脆皮面包？
Sure you don't want to try my Rock Au Gratin?
是有机的哦
It's organic.
谢谢了，我来的途中吃了一大块圆石
Thanks. I ate a boulder on the way in.
我们需要去遥远国的线路
We need directions to Far Far Away.
“我们”？谁说我要和你一起去？
"We"? Who said I was going with you?
我说的，人民指望着你 所以不要再躲避了
I did. People are counting on you, so don't try to weasel out of it.
如果那份差事真的那么好，你去做好了
If the job's so great, you do it.
你要明白，孩子 现在再也没有什么好人了
Understand this, kid. No more Mr. Nice Guy from here on out.
他就是你的所谓好人？
That was your Mr. Nice Guy?
是的，我会想念他的
Yeah, and I'm going to miss him.
为什么你不自己去恐吓村庄 别管我！
Why don't you go terrorize a village and leave me alone!
那就是怪物的爆发吗？ 在我没发飙前…
Was that a crack about ogres? You get your royal highness to Far Far Away...
你最好给我回遥远国去当国王 我该怎么发飙？
...before I kick it there! Now, which way am I kicking?
我可以告诉你，但由于你…
I could tell you, but since you're
正处于自我毁灭的怒火漩涡之中
in the midst of a self-destructive rage spiral,
告诉你是不负责任
it would be karmically irresponsible.
自我毁灭？ 你帮不帮我们？
Self-destructive? Are you going to help us or not?
肯定帮，但只有在你…
Most definitely, but only after you
进行了心灵之旅后！
take the journey to your soul!
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
要么就是这个，要么就进行心理治疗
It's either that or primal scream therapy.
好的，心灵之旅
All right. Journey to the soul.
现在，你们所有人…
Now, all of you,
都给我注视着这真理之火
look into the Fire of Truth
然后告诉我你们看到了什么
and tell me what you see.
哦，手势猜谜游戏！
Ooh, charades!
好，我看到了一个有肉桂卷的荷兰软糖馅饼
Okay, I see a Dutch fudge torte with cinnamon swirls!
好，怪物，该你了
Okay, monster... go for it.
我看到了一匹彩虹小马
I see a rainbow pony.
做得好！该你了，孩子
Excellent work! Now the boy.
这太废了
This is lame.
你才废！快试一下
You're lame! Now just go for it.
好的
Okay.
有一个小鸟还有个鸟爸爸，坐在鸟巢里
There's a baby bird and a father bird sitting in a nest.
好！继续！
Yes! Stay with it!
爸爸飞走了，他为什么单独留下了小鸟？
The dad just flew away. Why did he leave the little bird all alone?
小鸟试着飞行，但它不会飞
It's trying to fly, but it doesn't know how to.
它要掉下来了
It's going to fall!
你还真是个疯子 一塌糊涂
Proper head case you are. Really messed up.
好，我懂了，小鸟是我 我爸爸离开了，那又怎样
Okay, I get it. The bird's me. My dad left. So what?
听着，亚蒂
Look, Artie, um...
只是想给你们制造…
Just thought I'd help set the mood...
美好的心对心谈话的气氛
...for your big heart-to-heart chat.
我知道对于一件事还没准备好 是一种什么感觉
I know what it's like to not feel ready for something.
即使怪物也会觉得担心
Even ogres get scared.
你知道…偶尔
You know... once in a while.
我知道你要我成为国王，但我不能
I know you want me to be king, but I can't.
我不适合当国王，而且永远也不可能
I'm not cut out for it, and I never will be.
即使我亲身父亲也觉得我一无是处
Even my own dad knew I wasn't worth the trouble.
他第一时间把我扔到了那个学校
He dumped me at that school first chance he got...
我就再也没有听到过他的消息
...and I never heard from him again.
我爸爸也不配做父亲
My dad wasn't really the fatherly type, either.
我怀疑他比我的爸爸还差
I doubt he was worse than mine.
哦，是吗？
Oh, yeah?
我爸爸是个怪物，他想吃掉我
My father was an ogre. He tried to eat me.
我猜我本该意识到的
I guess I should have realized it.
他拿烧烤调味酱给我洗澡 拿苹果塞着我的嘴放我在床上
He bathed me in barbecue sauce and put me to bed with an apple in my mouth.
我想那真是太糟了
I guess that's pretty bad.
这也许很难相信…
It may be hard to believe,
我那显而易见迷人漂亮的外貌…
what, with my obvious charm and good looks,
但在过去一直认为我是个怪物
but people used to think I was a monster.
曾经一度，我也相信了他们
And for a long time, I believed them.
但后来
But after a while,
你学会了忽视别人怎么称呼你
you learn to ignore the names people call you
只要相信自己
and just trust who you are.
你知道的，你人很好，史莱克
You know... you're okay, Shrek.
你只要稍微减少大吼的次数 多用用肥皂就可以了
You just need to do a little less yelling and use a little more soap.
谢谢，亚蒂
Thanks, Artie.
肥皂是因为你发臭时…真的是太糟了
The soap's because you stink... really bad.
是啊，我明白了
Yeah... I got that.
这地方真是太脏了！
This place is filthy!
我感觉自己像是个流浪汉
I feel like a hobo.
不好意思，但这地方让我很难受
I'm sorry, but this isn't working for me.
你只关心你自己 你的态度不能对我们有任何帮助
Everything's always about you. It's not like your attitude is helping.
也许是我被选为国家最美的 这一事实打击了你
Maybe itjust bothers you I was voted fairest in the land.
你是说那次作弊的选美？
You mean in that rigged election?
得了吧，“莴苣姑娘 莴苣姑娘…
Give me a break. "Rapunzel, Rapunzel...
放下你的金色假发！”
...let down thy golden extensions!"
女士们，不要再相互抱怨了 我们要齐心协力
Ladies, let go of your petty complaints and let's work together!
我猜这计划就是我们毫无目的的…
So I guess the plan is we just wander aimlessly
在这臭气熏天的洞里闲逛直到我们腐烂
in this stinkhole until we rot.
不，我们要进去，去探明查明的目的
No, we get inside and find out what Oharming's up to.
我知道他是个混蛋
I know he's a jerk and everything,
但查明真是性感
but that Oharming makes me hotter than July.
就是那个！
That's it!
快点！这边！
Oome on! This way!
莴苣，等等
Rapunzel, wait!
查明，放开她
Oharming, let go of her.
我为什么要那么做？
But why would I want to do that?
什么？
What?
女士们，向你们遥远国的新女皇问好
Say hello, ladies, to the new Queen of Far Far Away.
莴苣，你怎么能这样？
Rapunzel, how could you?
妒忌吧？
Jealous much?
很快你就会回到当初…
Soon you'll be back where you started,
你擦地板，被锁在塔楼里的时代了
scrubbing floors or locked away in towers.
我会让你在这里多呆一个礼拜
That is, if I let you last the week.
波齐，你答应过不伤害他们的
Pookie, you promised not to hurt them.
等会儿，宝贝，我们晚点再说
Not here, kitten whiskers. Daddy will discuss it later.
见谅，我们要去赶演出
Now forgive us. We have a show to put on.
史莱克很快就回来了 你会后悔的
Shrek will be back soon, and you'll be sorry.
后悔？！
Sorry?!
你没意识到只要 史莱克一涉足遥远国…
Don't you realize once Shrek sets foot in Far Far Away...
他就完蛋了？
...he's doomed?
当心！他们有钢琴！
Look out! They got a piano!
把他们全杀了…除了那个胖的
Kill them all... except the fat one.
查明国王有特殊的主意留给你，怪物
King Oharming has something special in mind for you, ogre.
查明国王？
King Oharming?
攻击！
Attack!
亚蒂，蹲下！
Artie, duck!
准备好木板！
Ready the plank!
- 史莱克！ - 救命！
- Shrek! - Help!
冲啊！
Oowards!
查明把菲奥娜怎么了？
What has Oharming done with Fiona?
她已经束手就擒了
She's going to get what's coming to her.
你已经无能为力去救她了
And there ain't nothing you can do to stop him!
- 我们必须去救她 - 但我们离她太远了！
- We've got to save her. - But she's so far far away!
你自己回沃塞斯特雷吧，孩子
Get yourself back to Worcestershire, kid.
不，史莱克，等等 我有个主意
No, Shrek. Hold on. I've got an idea.
我是个嗡嗡小蜜蜂
I am a buzzing bee.
梅林先生？他们需要一个符咒…
Mr. Merlin? They need a spell to get them...
我是说我们需要回到遥远国
...I mean us, back to Far Far Away.
没门，我没有那种魔法能力了
Forget it. I don't have that kind of magic in me anymore.
拥抱一下怎样？ 那是最好的魔法
How about a hug? That's the best kind of magic.
梅林先生，求你了 我知道你可以的
Please. I know you can do it.
我说了没门！
I said forget it!
但…
But...
你怎么了？
What's with you?
这太难受了，你知道吗？
It's just so hard, you know?
他们需要回去 因为他们的国家正面临困境
They need to get back, 'cause their kingdom's in trouble.
因为那里有个坏人
'Oause there's a really bad man.
这太伤心了！
It's just so hard!
好了，别激动
Take it easy.
不！我想你肯定不理解！
No! I don't think you understand!
有个卑鄙的家伙正对 一群好人做着卑鄙的事
There's a mean person doing mean things to good people.
发发慈悲吧，老人
Have a heart, old man.
他们真的需要你帮助他们回去 为什么你不愿帮他们呢？！
They really need your help to get back. Why won't you help them?!
好的
Okay.
我去拿我的东西
I'll go get my things.
小菜一碟
Piece of cake.
那你想要点火腿鸡蛋吗？
Well, well. You want eggs with that ham?
我有点生疏了，因此这可能造成些副作用
I am a little rusty, so there could be some side effects.
- 副作用？ - 不用担心
- Side effects? - Don't worry.
不管什么副作用，无论这有多么痛苦
Whatever it is, no matter how excruciatingly painful,
我想最终这副作用会慢慢消失的
it will wear off eventually. I think.
- 哦，不 - 你确信？
- Oops. - You sure about this?
如果亚蒂相信他，那我也肯定相信
If Artie trusts him, that's good enough for me.
即使他的长袍没有盖住…
Even if his robe doesn't cover...
[玛咪玛咪，轰]
Alacritious expeditious...
[啊…儒咪！]
...a- zoomy-zoom-zoom!
让我们，帮我们的朋友快…
Let's help our friends get back...
回去！
...soon!
起作用了！
It worked!
自从大学后我就再也没经历过那种旅程了
I haven't been on a trip like that since college!
驴子？
Donkey?
什么？我牙齿里有什么东西吗？
What? Is something in my teeth?
哦，不！我被咒语弄成了那个二流伙伴了
Oh, no! I've been abracadabra-ed into a Fancy Feastin', second-rate sidekick!
至少你看起来不像是某种臃肿的玩偶
At least you don't look like some kind of bloated pinata!
你该考虑一下减肥！
You should think about going on a diet!
你该给自己弄条内裤 我感觉全都暴露了，很下流！
You should get yourself a pair of pants. I feel all exposed and nasty!
你们两个认为这很有趣吗？
So you two think this is funny?
我真的抱歉，伙计们
I'm really sorry, guys.
没关系，你把我们弄回来了，孩子
Don't be. You got us back, kid.
在安徒生童话里…
How in the Hans Ohristian Andersen
我也是该穿着这笨重的靴子到处走吗？
am I supposed to parade around in these goofy boots?
嘿，嘿，嘿！小心
Hey, hey, hey! Be very careful with those.
他们出自马德里最好的…
They were made in Madrid by the finest...
你会学会怎么控制这个的
You'll learn to control that.
真的，哦！你需要些安慰或是支持
Seriously. Ow! You need some comfort inserts or arch supports or something.
小心，我走在这儿 并且将一直走下去直到……
Watch it. I'm walking here and I'm gonna keep going until...
匹诺曹！
Pinocchio!
史莱克！救我！
Shrek! Help me!
- 发生什么事了？ - 查明和那些恶棍占领了这里！
- What happened? - Oharming and the villains took over!
菲奥娜和公主们走了 现在她…
Fiona and the Princesses got away. Now she's...
她怎么了？怎么了？！
She's what?! What?!
小猫，借我5块硬币
Puss! Loan me five bucks.
你听到了，帮他出来
You heard him. Help the brother out.
你看到我身上有口袋吗？
Do you see any pockets on me?
等等
Hold on a second.
我没办法，真的，我…我保证
I had no idea, really. I... I swear.
快！菲奥娜在哪里？
Quick! Where is Fiona?
查明把她关在了什么地方 你必须找到他！
Oharming has her locked away someplace. You have to find him!
他可能正在准备演出！
He's probably getting ready for the show!
等等，匹诺曹！什么演出？
Wait, Pinocchio! What show?
“从此以后过着幸福快乐的生活 ”
"It's a Happily Ever After After All".
“史莱克的最后演出”？
"Shrek's final performance"?
史莱克！你没告诉我们你会在演出里出现
Shrek! You didn't tell us you were in a play!
我想我真是太忙了，忘了提到了
I guess I've been so busy I forgot to mention it.
是那个怪物！抓住他！
The ogre! Get him!
别担心，老大，我来
Don't worry, jefe. I got this.
杀了他！
Uck! Kill it!
听着，难道你们不知道他是谁吗？ 你们怎么敢！
Look. Don't you know who he thinks he is? How dare you!
真是些土人
We're dealing with amateurs.
他是个明星，朋友们！哈罗？ 我很抱歉，史莱克先生
He's a star, people! Hello? I'm so sorry about this, Mr. Shrek.
我要生气了！
I'm going to lose it!
都准备好了吗？你得到更衣室的名单了吗？
Is everything ready? You did get the list for the dressing room?
早餐是塞有生切金枪鱼片的牛角面包
Breakfast croissant stuffed with seared sashimi tuna.
我希望你吃带有蜂蜜黄油的谷物
And I hope you have the saffron corn with jalapeno honey butter.
我们的名人没有蜂蜜黄油的话…
Our client cannot get into his proper emotional state
会达不到好的状态
withoutjalapeno honey butter!
我生气了
I just lost it.
他们该和人力的南希谈谈
They should talk to Nancy in Human Resources.
哦，我保证我们有很多话要告诉南希
Oh, we will have much to say to Nancy, I promise!
“用这把剑，我…”，不
"With this sword, I do..." No. "With..."
“用这把剑，我将击倒你！”
"With this sword, I do smote thee!"
“击倒”这个词对吗？“击到”？
Is "smote" the right word? "Smoot"?
我不认为有这个词
I don't think that's a word.
也许我该“击倒”他，我们再试一下
Maybe I should just "smite" him. Let's try this again. Now...
史莱克攻击我，我假装害怕
Shrek attacks me. I pretend to be afraid.
“现在这个国家将从此得到他们应得的幸福 去死吧，怪物！”
"Now the kingdom will get the happily ever after they deserve. Die, ogre!"
哦，感觉不够真实！
Blah, blah, blah. Oh, itjust doesn't feel real enough!
谁要求你停止跳舞？！
Who told you to stop dancing?!
眨眼，转圈
Wink and turn.
你躺在那里干吗？起来！老实点！
What are you laying around for? Get up! Honestly!
我们从此以后的幸福就要实现了，妈咪
Our happily ever after is nearly complete, Mummy.
我向你保证…
And I assure you...
这个国家的每个人会为 我们等待的每一秒…
...the people of this kingdom will pay dearly for every second...
付出代价
...we've had to wait.
断腿
Break a leg.
再想想，还是我来弄断你条腿吧
On second thought, let me break it for you.
谢天谢地，我还以为你不会及时回来了呢
Thank goodness. I was afraid you wouldn't get back in time.
菲奥娜在哪里？
Where's Fiona?
不要担心，她和其他的人都很安全
Don't worry. She and the others are safe... for now.
我猜猜，亚瑟
Let me guess. Arthur.
事实上是叫亚蒂
It's Artie, actually.
这孩子就是遥远国的新国王？
This boy is supposed to be the new King of Far Far Away?
多悲哀啊
How pathetic.
不要动，我才不会手发抖
Stand still, so I won't make a mess.
查明，住手！我在这里 你得到了你想要的
Oharming, stop! I'm here now. You got what you wanted.
这和他没关系
This isn't about him.
那和谁有关？ 我才应该是国王，对吗？
Then who's it about? I'm supposed to be king, right?
你其实不是下一任王座的继承人
You weren't really next in line for the throne.
我才是
I was.
但你说过国王亲自点名要我继任
But you said the King asked for me personally.
不完全正确
Not exactly.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
该说的我都说了，好了吗？
I said whatever I had to say, all right?
我不适合这个位置 因此需要某个傻瓜来代替我
I wasn't right for the job, so I needed some fool to replace me.
而你正好合适，你走吧！
And you fit the bill. So just go!
原来你一直在耍我
You were playing me the whole time.
你理解的很快，孩子
You catch on real fast, kid.
也许你不是我想像中的那么失败
Maybe you're not as big of a loser as I thought.
你知道，曾经一度…
You know, for a minute...
- 我真的以为… - 什么？
...I actually thought... - What?
他在意你？他是个怪物
That he cared about you? He's an ogre.
你期盼什么呢？
What did you expect?
对付孩子你可真有一套啊，史莱克
You really do have a way with children, Shrek.
Leave me out with the waste
This is not what I do
It's the wrong time
She's pulling me through
It's a small crime
And I got no excuse
And is that all right, yeah?
Is that all right with you?
Is that all right, yeah?
If I give my gun away when it's loaded?
If you don't shoot it how am I supposed to hold it?
Is that all right? Is that all right?
Is that all right with you?
No.
要是我们像我说的呆在原处不动
Had we stayed put like I suggested,
我们现在就正拿着心形杯喝茶呢
we'd be sipping tea out of little heart-shaped cups.
是啊，是啊，心形杯
Yeah, heart-shaped cups.
吃着带罗甘莓的煎饼
And eating crumpets smothered with loganberries.
是啊，罗甘莓
Yeah, loganberries.
- 闭嘴，辛迪 - 是啊，闭嘴
- Shut up, Oindy. - Yeah, shut up.
- 不，你闭嘴 - 少管闲事
- No, you shut up. - Stay out of this.
谁在乎谁来掌管国家？
Who cares who's "running the kingdom"?
- 我关心 - 你们都该关心
- I care. - You should all care.
我记住你们的徽章编号了，铁罐！
I have your badge number, tin can!
- 驴子？ - 公主！
- Donkey? - Princess!
猫咪？
Puss?
我才是猫咪，粘在了这个丑恶的身体里
I am Puss, stuck here inside this hideous body.
我才是我！
And I'm me!
但你是…
But you're...
一切都糟透了，事情是这样的
Everything's fruity in the loops, but what happened is
我们去了中学，船撞毁了
we went to high school, the boat crashed
然后我们一个魔法师施了魔法
and we got bippity-boppity-booped by the magic man.
可怜的家伙
You poor sweet things.
我没明白
I don't get it.
这只猫变成了闻起来像臭脚的驴子 什么不明白的？
The cat turned into a little horse that smells like feet. What's to get?
谁死了？
Who dat?
史莱克呢？
Where's Shrek?
查明抓住了他，他计划 今晚在整个国家面前杀了他
Oharming has him. He plans to kill Shrek tonight in front of the whole kingdom!
好了，各位，我们需要找到条出去的路
All right, everyone. We need to find a way out now.
你说的对，女士们，各就各位
You're right. Ladies, assume the position!
你们在干吗？
What are you doing?
等着被救
Waiting to be rescued.
你在开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
我们还能怎么做呢？我们只是四个…
What else can we do? We're just four...
我是说三个漂亮的公主
...I mean three, super-hot princesses...
两个马戏团小丑，一个怀孕的怪物 还有个老太婆
...two circus freaks, a pregnant ogre and an old lady!
不好意思，老太婆要爆发了
Excuse me. Old lady coming through.
妈妈！
Mom!
你认为你没有从你父亲那里 学到了战斗技巧，是吗？
You didn't think you got your fighting skills from your father, did you?
不好意思，我想那还有一面墙
Excuse me. There's still one more.
你先躺下休息一下吧
Why don't you just lie down?
好了，女士们，从这里出去
Okay, girls, from here on out...
我们自己管好自己
...we take care of business ourselves.
先生们女士们，查明阁下的 遥远国剧场将隆重呈现…
The Far Far Away Theatre at the Charming Pavilion is proud to present...
“从此以后过着幸福快乐的生活”
..."It's A Happily Ever After After AII."
市民们，享受这梦幻般的夜晚
Enjoy your evening of theatrical reverie, citizen.
剧场里不允许吃零食和饮料
Oi! No food or beverages in the theater!
各就各位！
Places, everyone!
轻点！
Easy!
对不起，我想跟小家伙炫耀一下
Sorry. I was showing off for the little one.
带了孩子来上班，过来，美女
It's Bring Your Kids to Work Day. Oome here, beautiful.
她继承了你的眼睛
Well, she's got your eye.
谁会想到像我这种怪物 能拥有像你一样特别的东西呢
Who would have thought a monster like me deserved something as special as you?
Little birdies, take wing
Flitting down from the trees they appear
And to chirp in my ear
All because I sing
冲啊！冲！
Move it! Go!
我的孩子们！
My babies!
救命！
Help!
嘿，怎么样？
Hey, how's it goin'?
O到K，危险已经全部清除
O to the K. The coast is clear.
我们行动吧，出去，摧毁小队
Let's do this. Go, Team Dynamite!
我认为我们已经同意了 使用超级无敌酷这个小队名字
I thought we agreed to use the name Team Super Oool.
我记得是叫帅气小队
I recall it was Team Awesome.
我投票选了阿尔法狼中队
I voted for Team Alpha Wolf Squadron.
好了，好了！从此以后
Okay! From henceforth,
我们就是阿尔法超级帅气无敌摧毁狼中队
we will be Team Alpha Super Awesome Oool Dynamite Wolf Squadron.
那边有个奇怪的陌生小女孩盯着我们看
Ach de liebe! There is some strange little girl over there staring at us!
亚蒂！
Artie!
等等，等等！
Wait, wait!
你的怒火呢，先生？
Where is the fire, senor?
拜托，别装的那么无辜
Please. Don't act so innocent.
你从一开始就知道怎么回事 却一直没说
You both knew what was going on and kept it to yourselves.
事情并不是那样的
It's not like it seems.
不是那样？我认为已经很清楚了
It's not? I think it seems pretty clear.
他在利用我，就是那么回事
He was using me. That's all.
利用你？你真的没明白
Using you? You really don't get it.
史莱克是为了保护你才这么说的
Shrek only said those things to protect you.
不然查明会杀了你的，亚蒂！ 史莱克救了你的命
Oharming was going to kill you, Artie! Shrek saved your life.
灯光对准！
Oue the spot!
我孤独在这儿等待
I wait alone up here
被关了又一天
I'm trapped another day
被锁在这里，请让我出去
Locked up here, please set me free
我的新生活我快看见
My new life I almost see
一个城堡，你和我
A castle, you and me
是的，一个城堡，你和我
Yes, a castle, you and me
天使！
Oherubs!
是的，我在我的帝王战马上
Tis I, Tis I Upon my regal steed
公主，我的爱
Princess, my love
最终你会自由的 我很强壮
At last you shall be freed I'm strong
很勇敢，正赶来救你
And brave And dashing my way there
用我的速度！用我的力量！ 用我那柔软有弹性的头发！
With speed! With might! With soft and bouncy hair!
- 穿过恶劣的沙漠 - 炎热！
- Through the blistering desert - Hot!
- 渡过狂暴的大海 - 潮湿！
- Across the stormiest sea - Wet!
面对如此恶劣的生物
Facing creatures so vile
恶心！
Foul!
这样你就有机会注视着我
So you can gaze upon me!
我知道你会来救我
I knew you'd come for me
现在我们终于见面了
And now we finally meet
我知道你会等
I knew you'd wait
会接受我的爱
And from my plate of love you'd eat
这个丑陋的魔鬼是谁？ 谁敢如此粗鲁的来干涉？
Who is this terribly ugly fiend Who so rudely intervened?
查明会战斗还是逃跑？
Will Charming fight or flee?
请救我！
Please rescue me!
救我离开这个怪物！
From this monstrosity!
你别怕，亲爱的！ 我会把这怪物切成肉片
Fear thee not, honey lamb! I will slice this thing up like a ham!
哦，孩子
Oh, boy.
你将进入一个你…
You are about to enter a world of pain
从未感受过的痛苦世界
With which you are not familiar!
没有比你的拙劣表演更痛苦的了
It can't be any more painful than your lousy performance.
“受死吧，恶心的怪物”
"Prepare, foul beast."
受死吧，恶心的怪物，你的死期已到
Prepare, foul beast, your time is done!
你能不能先杀了我然后再唱？
Oould you kill me and then sing?
安静！
Be quiet!
我只是和你开玩笑 那真是个漂亮的连衣裤
I'm just having fun with you. That's actually a very nice leotard.
谢谢
Thank you.
是照男人的尺寸来做的吗？
Do they come in men's sizes?
真好笑啊
Now that be funny!
够了！
Enough!
现在你终于知道…
Now you'll finally know what it's like...
对你来说宝贵的东西被夺走…
...to have everything you worked for...
是一种什么感觉了
...everything that's precious to you, taken away.
现在你会知道我是什么感觉
Now you'll know how I felt.
香肠卷
Sausage roll!
祈求猫咪的仁慈吧！
Pray for mercy from Puss!
还有驴子！
And Donkey!
D
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, honey.
对不起，我们来晚了，你还好吗？
Sorry we're late. You okay?
你在这里好多了
Much better, now that you're here.
那么，查明，你想放开我 让我们进行真正的怪物对男人的决斗吗？
So, Oharming, you want to let me out of these so we can settle this ogre-to-man?
哦，那听上去很有趣 但我有个更好的主意
Ooh, that sounds fun. But I have a better idea.
不！放开我！
No! Let go of me!
这次不会让你毁了一切的，怪物 杀了他
You will not ruin things this time, ogre. Kill it.
大家，住手！
Everybody, stop!
哦，又是什么？！
Oh, what is it now?!
亚蒂？
Artie?
谁说我们必须要以这种方式解决问题？
Who thinks we need to settle things this way?
你们想一生都做恶棍吗？
You mean you want to be villains your whole lives?
但我们就是恶棍！ 这是我们唯一所明白的
But we are villains! It's the only thing we know.
你从没希望做别的什么吗？
You never wish you could be something else?
你说的容易，你又不是给施了魔法的树
Easy for you to say. You're not some evil enchanted tree.
你个蠢人！别听他的！攻击！
You morons! Don't listen to him! Attack!
斯蒂夫的意思是如果全世界都讨厌你
What Steve means is it's hard to come by honest work
那么很难得到好工作
when the whole world's against you.
对的，谢谢，爱德
Right. Thanks, Ed.
很公平，你说的对 我不是棵会说话的树
Fair enough. You're right. I'm not a talking tree.
但你要知道…
But you know...
一个好朋友曾经告诉我…
...a good friend once told me...
别人对待你像对待恶棍…
...just because people treat you like a villain, or an ogre...
或是怪物，或者像对待一个失败者
...orjust some loser...
这并不意味你就是
...doesn't mean you are one.
最重要的是你自己怎么看你自己
What matters most is what you think of yourself.
如果有什么你真的想要的 或是你想成为的…
If there's something you really want, or someone you want to be...
唯一能阻拦你的就是你自己
...the only person standing in your way is you.
- 我自己？ - 抓住他！
- Me? - Get him!
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
我的意思是你们每个人…
What I mean is each of you...
都有自己的路
...is standing in your own way.
我一直想演奏长笛
I always wanted to play the flute.
我想要在法国开个温泉浴场
I'd like to open up a spa... in France!
我想种水仙花，很漂亮的
I grow daffodils. And they're beautiful.
一个新的时代终于来临了！
A new era finally begins!
现在你们…
Now all of you...
向你们的国王鞠躬！
...bow before your King!
你需要练习一下瞄准
You need to work on your aim.
这本该是我的幸福生活！
This was supposed to be my happily ever after!
那我想你需要继续寻找了…
Well, you need to keep looking...
因为我不会放弃我的幸福生活
...because I'm not giving up mine.
妈咪？
Mommy?
如果你想要就给你了
It's yours if you want it.
但这次你自己选择
But this time it's your choice.
亚瑟！
Author!
亚蒂！亚蒂！亚蒂！
Artie! Artie! Artie! Artie!
不好意思，那是我的座位
Excuse me. That's my seat.
好了，大魔法师先生 现在是时候纠正错误了！
Okay, Senor Hocusy-Pocusy, the time has come to rectify some wrongs!
尽管我很享受猫的沐浴
Though I have been enjoying these cat baths.
请说你不喜欢
Please say you didn't.
好的！听着
All right! Look.
你们可能会感到被掐了一下 也许还会肠子不舒服
You'll feel a pinch and possibly lower intestinal discomfort...
但这应该有效
...but this should do the trick.
- 是你吗？ - 我又变回我自己啦！
- Are you? - I'm me again!
- 我不再是你啦！ - 好啦！
- And I am not you! - All right!
唉
Oops.
啊，没关系
Ah, never mind.
我怎么告诉你的？ 这孩子会成为一个伟大的国王
What did I tell you? The kid's going to be a great king.
确实，你本来也会是的
Well, for what it's worth, you would have, too.
我心里还有更重要的事情
I have something much more important in mind.
最终
Finally.
爸爸
Dada.
Was I wrong about the world? It's a beautiful new place
嘿嘿，我闻到了小史莱克的味道！
I smell Shrek Junior!
Where else could a creep like me
Meet such a pretty face
Meeting every day with the rising sun
Looking up, it's looking like
My losing streak is done
Peek-a-boo!
跳啊，跳，宝贝
A bouncy, bouncy, boy!
Used to always feel like
Wished that I was dressed better
婴儿在哪里？
Where's the baby?
Never had a lot of luck Until I finally met her
Meeting every day with the rising sun
Looking up, it's looking like
My losing streak is done
那…我们现在该干吗呢？
Well... what shall we do now?
我来吧
I got it.
Puss and Donkey, baby! Once again, come on!
I want to thank you for letting me be myself
Again!
Look at my hips!
I want to thank you for letting me be myself
Again!
- Break it down! - Let's go!
Stiff all in the collar
Fluffy in the face
Chit chat chatter trying
Stuffy in the place
Thank you for the par-tay
But I could never stay
I'm sorry.
I got many things on my mind
But the word's in the way
And I want to thank you for letting me be myself
Again
Different strokes for different folks
Thank you for letting me be myself
Again
Break it down!
Puss and Donkey, baby! Puss and Donkey, baby!
Puss and Donkey, baby!
Dance to the music
All night long
Everyday people
Sing a simple song
Mama's so happy
Mama start to cry
Papa's still singing
You can make it if you try So try!
Thank you for letting me be myself
Again
Oome on, Donkey. Do something right!
Put the hoofs together! Put the hoofs together!
Stomp your boots, baby! Stomp your boots, baby! Stomp your boots, baby!
Thank you for letting me be myself
Again
I want to thank you for letting me be myself
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Want to thank you Just to be my
Because I just want to be my... See?
Can I, can I thank you! Can I
Yes! Yes!